Guide to the Rice University Staff Advisory Committee records, 1992-2010 UA 219
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Staff Advisory Committee records
1992-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 219
3 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Working files of the Rice University Staff Advisory Committee, 1992-2010. (5 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
The Staff Advisory Committee at Rice University was set up in 1992 by Caroline Garcia, Director of Human Resources, as a way to increase communication between the staff and the administration.
As of 2011, fifteen full-time university staff members are appointed to serve on the Staff Advisory Committee (SAC) of Rice University to fulfill its primary mission: making work at Rice more enjoyable and productive. Composed of four subcommittees, SAC aims to provide personal growth and development, not to mention a little camaraderie, through monthly lunchtime programs known as Brown Bag and Lunch Bunch, the annual RiceFest benefits event, and the summertime Ice Cream Social. All Rice staff members are welcome to join any of the SAC's four subcommittees.
Subcommittees include: Communications, Employee Activities, Staff Development, and Rice Fest.
SAC's mission is to facilitate open lines of communication between the university's administration and staff by:
* Providing a forum for hearing and reviewing staff concerns and interests, and bringing applicable issues to the attention of the administration * Proposing ways to improve university staff relations, including ideas that originate from within the staff * Recommending staff appointees to the President and/or the Associate Vice President for Human Resources to serve on university committees * Acting, in general, to help make Rice University's education community an efficient, fulfilling, and supportive environment for employment * Supporting the university's formal mission statement as defined by the Board of Trustees
Excerpted from http://sac.rice.edu/ on March 11, 2011.
Scope and Contents
These records include the working files of the Staff Advisory Committee at Rice University, 1992-2010, with such formats as meeting agendas, notes, correspondence and flyers. The files are not complete for this time period, but do offer a representative sample of the work done by this committee. Rice Fest is perhaps the best represented here of the activities programmed by the Staff Advisory Committee.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transfered to the library by members of the Staff Advisory Committee in 1998 and 2011.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
letters (correspondence); floppy disks; directories; minutes (administrative records); scrapbooks
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: 1992-1998, 117398
  - 1992-1993 Chairman's notebook files, 117400 (Box 1)
  - By laws drafts, 117401 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - By laws master copy with diskette, 117402 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1990s, 117403 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and policies, drafts, 117404 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1993-1994, 117406 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1994-1995, 117407 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1995-1998, 117408 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Supporting materials for meetings, 117409 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Membership rosters, 1990s, 117410 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Publicity, 117411 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rice Fest, 1992-1995, 117412 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Staff Advisor, 1993-1996, 117413 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Annual reports, 1996-1997, 117414 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Nominations sub-committee University Standing Committees and SAC, 1996-1998, 117415 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - By-laws review, 1999-2000, 117417 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rice Fest, 1999-2000, 117422 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Series II: 2002-2010, 117399
  - SAC meeting agenda and preparation documents, Feb. 2000, 117421 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Staff Development Sub-committee, 2003-2004, 117423 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 5th Annual Harvest Handoff & Baking Contest Cookbook, Oct. 26, 2004, 117416 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Working papers binder, FY 2004-2005, 117418 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Call to Conversation forum, 2005, 117420 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Working file, 2005-2006, 117419 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Co-chair records, 2005-2006, 117424 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - SAC event comment cards, 2010, 117425 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes/ Working Files, 2008 - 2009; 146983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Service Awards scrapbook, 2001, 127373 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Awards for staff members of 5 to 40 years of service. Recipients of the 40 years of service this year included: Elizabeth baber, Jim Castaneda, Alan Grob and Walter Isle. A full list of all award recipients is included in the scrapbook.
- Series III: Addenda, 1999-2001